Welcome.
어서 오세요
It's week three.
3주 차예요
It's day four.
4일째예요
We are back on the adventure in open source land, back investigating how to run inference over open
오픈 소스 랜드로 돌아왔습니다 오픈 소스 모델을 어떻게 추론하는지 조사하고
source models.
있죠
And today it is time to look at the model class in Hugging Face.
오늘은 얼굴 껴안기 모범 수업을 해 볼게요
We talked originally about pipeline API, the high level API.
파이프라인 API 얘기를 했었죠 상위 수준 API요
Then we started talking about the low level API, beginning with Tokenizers and now onto the model.
그다음에는 낮은 수준의 API 얘기를 했습니다 토큰라이저로 시작해서 모델로 넘어갔죠
So what can you already do?
그래서 뭘 할 수 있는데요?
Of course, in addition to coding with frontier models, building multimodal AI assistants or you can
물론 지금은 개척 시대 모델의 코딩 외에도 다중 모듈 인공지능 비서를 제작하고
now do is use hugging faces, pipelines and tokenizers today.
있습니다 현재는 얼굴 포옹이나 파이프라인 토큰라이저를 사용하죠
New skills, new classes.
새로운 기술에 새로운 수업이죠
We're going to get into the models part of hugging face, which is when you actually create a transformer
얼굴을 안는 것의 모델 부분으로 들어가겠습니다 변압기를 생성하고 텍스트를 생성하기
and run it to generate text.
위해 실행하는 거죠 get it
And we'll be comparing results across five different models.
다섯 가지 모델로 결과를 비교할 거예요
I'm actually going to be doing three of them with you and leaving you to experiment with the other two,
제가 3개를 같이 할 거예요 나머지 2개는 당신이 실험해 보세요
uh, so that you can have an extra exercise, but I'll have all of the code ready for you.
추가 운동을 할 수 있게요 코드는 다 준비해 둘게요
Um, so it should be a lot of fun.
재미있을 것 같아요
So the models then to introduce them.
모델들이 그들을 소개하죠
We are going to again be working with llama 3.1 from meta, their flagship and groundbreaking model.
라마 3을 다시 작업하게 될 거예요 기함이자 획기적인 모델인 메타에서 한 대 왔어요
We are going to be looking at Phi three, which is Microsoft's open source model, and Gemma from Google.
마이크로소프트의 파이3 오픈 소스 모델과 구글의 젬마를 살펴볼 거예요
It's a the small.
스몰 사이즈예요
The small cousin of Gemini is Google's Gemma.
제미니의 사촌이 구글의 제마죠
There are two other models that I'll be leaving you with to experiment with on your own.
여러분이 직접 실험해 볼 모델이 두 개 더 있어요
One of them is Mistral from Mistral and the other, the other is the powerhouse that is Quinn two.
하나는 미스트럴의 미스트럴이고 다른 하나는 퀸의 2번 선수예요
And I hope that you will enjoy using Quantu.
취안토를 즐겨 보세요
So we're also going to be covering three aspects of working with open source models in the hugging face
오픈 소스 모델과의 세 가지 측면도 다룰 겁니다 얼굴 프레임워크에서요
Um, the first of them is called quantization.
첫 번째는 퀀타이즈라는 거예요
And this is about reducing the precision of the weights in the model so that it is easier to fit into
이것은 모델의 무게의 정밀도를 줄이는 것입니다. 메모리에 쉽게 맞추고 로드도
memory and loads in and also can run faster.
쉽게 하고 더 빠르게 달릴 수 있죠.
So quantization, a very important technique that allows us to work with, say, a one of the lower
퀀타이즈는 아주 중요한 기술로 GPU 하위 제품 중 하나로 작업할 수
end GPU boxes.
있게 해주죠
and when we get to training, it's going to be absolutely critical to be able to use quantization,
트레이닝을 할 때 반드시 퀀타이즈를 사용할 수 있어야
to be able to train large open source models.
합니다 큰 오픈 소스 모델을 훈련하기 위해서요
In fact, you've heard me saying, now the Q Laura, that is the name of the technique that we're going
아까도 말했지만 Q 로라는 우리가 몇 주 후에
to be using in a couple of weeks time.
사용할 기술의 이름이에요
And the Q and Q, Laura stands for quantization.
질문과 질문, 로라는 수량화의 약자예요
So we will be coming up against quantization a few times on this journey.
이번 여정에서 퀀타이즈와 몇 번 부딪힐 거예요
Today we're also going to be looking inside a model.
오늘은 모델 내부도 살펴볼 거예요
So generally again this is a class that is more practical than theoretical.
다시 말씀드리지만 이론보다는 실용적인 수업이에요
But this will be one of those moments.
하지만 지금이 바로 그런 순간이에요
And we'll just take a peek inside at what what do the PyTorch layers look like that sit behind the hugging
포옹하는 트랜스포머 라이브러리 뒤에 있는 파이토치 층은 어떤 모습일지 살짝
face Transformers library.
들여다볼게요
And then also, we're so familiar with streaming at this point that it hardly needs to be said that
지금은 스트리밍에 익숙해서 결과를 스트리밍할 수 있다고 말할
we want to be able to stream results.
필요도 없어요
So I will show you how you can work with open source models to stream results as well.
결과 스트리밍을 위해 오픈 소스 모델로 작업하는 방법을 보여드리죠
So these are some of the little extra bits that we're going to look into in our voyage into running
이게 이번 항해에서 살펴볼 추가 사항입니다 얼굴을 껴안는 하위
inference over the lower level APIs for hugging face.
레벨 API를 실행하는 거죠
There's quite enough talk.
얘기는 충분히 했어요
Let's get to it.
Get it, get it 해 보죠